[engine starts]
[engine revving]
[Jerry] This is a 1968 Firebird 400
in solar red.
The 400 was the most powerful Firebird
you could buy in 1968.
[tires screeching]
Picture yourself.
You're a kid living
in Syosset, Long Island.
You're a comedy nerd.
Your life is a total zero.
You sit home every day
watching Mike Douglas,
Merv Griffin, Johnny Carson,
and David Letterman.
What car could possibly break you out
of your miserable loserness?
This is that car.
Because it's got rally wheels,
hood-mounted tach,
auxiliary gauge clusters,
sport wood steering wheel,
rear mount antenna,
and custom exhaust tips.
But at over $3,000, it's not something
you'd ever be able to afford.
Your parents aren't
going to buy it for you.
It's not even that good
of a car to begin with.
But you live on Long Island,
you don't know any better.
This is as high as you could dream.
The boy that I'm talking about
is my very special guest this week,
Mr. Judd Apatow,
the very talented comedian,
filmmaker, and comedy super-geek.
If he had a car like this,
we would never have all this
fantastic entertainment that he has made.
So, today, I'm going to give him a chance
to see what it might have been like
if he would've had this car at that time,
and could have made his escape
from Syosset.
[phone ringing]
-[Judd] Yes, sir?
-[Jerry] Judd?
Nobody really knows
if it's Apatoe or Apatow.
[Judd] It's Apatow,
but if people say Apatoe,
-I don't mind, 'cause it sounds fancier.
-[Jerry] Sounds like a dance step.
[Judd] I wasn't sure
if coffee implied hamburger or not.
-And a chocolate shake.
-[Jerry] Sure.
Chocolate shake and a burger
for breakfast, I love that idea.
[Judd chuckles] Let's do it.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Hello.
[Jerry] Wow, look at this.
-So much stuff.
-[Judd] There's stuff, yeah.
I like to see everything.
[upbeat jazz music playing]
-[Jerry] Is this where you write?
-Yes, this is where I write.
I try to do it in the morning
before it gets too busy.
That is hilarious.
[Judd] That is 1989.
I was doing stand-up then.
And then I found
a picture of us with Garry...
-[Jerry] Oh, my God.
-[Judd] ...at The Larry Sanders Show.
Then here's the other thing
I was gonna show you.
On your episode, you said to Garry,
"What becomes of
all of David Brenner's jokes?"
Material, yeah.
So you go,
"What happens to all of Garry's jokes?"
I have them.
This is all of his, like, set lists
and joke journals, and his Rolodex.
Ah! Garry's service, he had a service.
Back then, you'd call your service,
"Do I have any calls?"
-Yeah.
-[both laughing]
"Any calls for me?"
[Judd] And I have a funny one of Jay.
-[Jerry] You're 16 there?
-[Judd] Yeah.
Jay said it looked like
To Catch a Predator.
[both laughing]
You know, I interviewed you
twice back then.
I did 50 of those interviews,
from Jay, and from Harold Ramis,
and John Candy,
and I just grilled everybody.
I didn't even air
almost any of the interviews.
They were just for me.
I knew no one cared.
And it really was like a textbook,
and when I went to college, I thought,
"I don't need to know any of this."
Because people like you explained
everything to me in great detail.
And it really... That's how I felt.
I left college after a year and a half.
You know what I found that's so funny?
I was going through my hoarding.
-This is when I interviewed you...
-[Jerry gasps]
[Judd] ...in 1983.
[Jerry] We gotta do the same pose.
[Judd] That's it.
-[Jerry] Let's get rolling.
-Let's get a hamburger.
[upbeat rock music playing]
Things like this, that are sexy,
make me uncomfortable.
-Because I don't feel sexy.
-Of course you don't, you're not.
But that's where the car takes over.
I have no interest
in good-looking people in movies.
-No.
-I would like Bourne Identity much better
-if it starred George Wendt.
-laughs]
I had no car. My dad didn't buy me a car.
Of course you had no car.
It's written all over your face.
That's my car.
-[Jerry] That's fine.
-Does not let me down.
It doesn't lift you up, either.
[engine starts, revs]
-Nice.
-You're in Syosset.
-I'm in Syosset.
-And you get into this.
Mom, Dad,
"When are you coming back, Judd?"
-"I have no idea."
-Yeah. [laughs]
[Judd] I remember I was just starting out,
and I did this bit I used to do
which was a letter to my starving child
in a South American country.
And I slipped it in
right before bringing you on,
-how an emcee does, try to get a joke in.
-Yeah, yeah.
And you walked on stage,
and you went, "That was funny."
And it kept me going for about two years.
[upbeat music playing]
What do you want from life at this point?
-Me?
-Yeah. Well, who else?
[laughing]
What kind of...
Am I talking to the dashboard?
-You've achieved so much.
-Yeah.
Dreams you never even had. So now...
-Now what?
Well, you know, I started doing
stand-up again two years ago,
and it's very difficult and really fun
to do something
that you've always wanted to do,
so in a way,
I feel like I made all those movies
just to get good spots at The Improv.
-That's hilarious.
-[Judd laughs]
So, you did
The Tonight Show with Jimmy Fallon.
-Yes.
-It was a terrific set.
Any accurate drawing of a Jewish person
is inherently anti-Semitic.
[audience laughing]
A perfect drawing of me
is like Nazi propaganda.
[audience laughing loudly]
That really was the only dream.
-To do The Tonight Show.
-The Tonight Show.
[Judd] Right before I did it,
Louis C.K. sent me an email,
and it explained exactly
how to do The Tonight Show.
With specific directions.
Like, "When you walk out to the music,
don't bob your head,
the music's not for you."
I am so excited
about what we're going to eat.
Who decided that
a hamburger's not a breakfast food?
Humans.
[inaudible]
[Judd] So, my mom,
she was having financial problems
and she needed to buy a car.
And she got a Mercedes.
And I said, "Mom,
why didn't you buy a Camry
so that you had money
to spend on things like food?"
And she said, "Because I'm not an animal."
[Jerry laughing]
[upbeat music playing]
It's fun when you first show a movie
and the audience likes it, the first time.
But then it's kind of gone.
A movie just drifts off,
and at some point,
you feel like you didn't make it.
It's not like stand-up where you can
experience it every night with the crowd,
and you have this
visceral human experience.
The funny thing about making a movie
is you have to convince people
that it will make money.
-Right.
-But you don't know if it will.
When a movie bombs,
you feel pain for a while.
I always say if you make
three mega bombs,
you're out of the business.
If you have a huge bomb,
they'll let you do another.
If that bombs,
they'll let you do a cheaper one,
and if that bombs, you're done.
[Jerry] The idea of this show
is we have a good time.
I've tried to remove
all the annoyances of a talk show.
-Yes.
-The first being,
I don't really want
to talk to this person.
[both laughing]
-So, all guests you like?
-Yeah.
[upbeat music playing]
[inaudible]
Isn't this great? How funny is this guy?
[Judd] Harvey Korman,
-maybe the funniest of all time.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
[inaudible]
Oh, look at Leno. I always hate when
they trick you into doing the toilet shot.
Never do the toilet shot.
Look at the Carson shot!
Look at the look on his face, though.
You're entertained
just by the look in his eye.
That's what I thought was funny,
is Shandling seemed like
they were like buddies from moment one,
like they were comfortable.
-Garry was very, very poised.
-Yeah.
-I envied Garry's poise.
I didn't have that.
Oh, did you ever just feel like
you landed in heaven?
-Yeah.
-We're in heaven.
Have you ever seen a table that wants
hamburgers and chocolate shakes on it?
-No, this is it.
-This is it.
[waiter] Wanna start with coffee?
-[Jerry] Yeah.
-And a chocolate milkshake.
[whirring]
People don't generally recognize me.
But if I walk down the street, and
somebody says, "Are you Judd Apatow?"
if I say no, they go, "All right."
[both laughing]
One of the reasons why I stopped
doing stand-up and performing
is that Adam Sandler and I
auditioned for Jim Henson.
And afterwards, I heard,
"Jim Henson doesn't want
to give you the job.
He thought you lacked warmth."
It's like Hitler telling you
you don't have the killer instinct.
Now, when you stopped doing stand-up,
how many year break, 22 years?
I took a 22-year break,
but I hated not being
part of the community.
This never happens.
-This?
-This never happens.
You're not with other comedians,
the whole social--
But if you have a comedian in the movie?
But then you shoot for three months,
and then you work on it
-for a year and a half, alone.
-Oh, I see.
I was so happy with how
Freaks and Geeks came out
that in my head, I thought,
"My career is basically over.
I accomplished
what I wanted to accomplish,
and everything else is gravy."
-Wow.
-And so nothing else matters.
I can experiment, I can do anything,
because I did what I wanted
to do perfectly, once.
That is very healthy.
I don't think
you need to go to the shrink anymore.
I think you're right.
Are you anti-therapy?
Kind of, yeah.
Because it seems self-perpetuating.
I could talk with anybody.
You could say, "What's bothering you?"
I'll go for an hour.
[both laugh]
[soft jazz music playing]
[Judd] When Garry died,
they decided not to do an autopsy,
because what was really the point?
And then I see Albert Brooks,
and he's like,
"Was there an autopsy?"
[Jerry laughs]
I'm like, "No,
they decided there was no reason."
And he's like, "Well, there is a reason,
so I could know what happened
and try to avoid it."
[chuckling]
At the memorial, everybody who spoke,
all said things
that Garry had said to them,
and every person who spoke killed with it.
Garry's lawyer rips the roof
off the place quoting Garry.
[both laughing]
You know, people responded
at Garry's memorial to you and Garry.
-And it's a big way.
-That's nice.
There's something about him
that encompasses the human struggle.
Like, he was trying so hard to be happy,
and to find peace,
and to let go of his ego.
You're making me sad.
And he touched people very deeply.
And Garry always said,
"The Larry Sanders Show
is about people who love each other,
but show business gets in the way."
I need that cheeseburger so bad right now.
How hard is it to make a cheeseburger?
It's a diner. Where is it?
[bell rings]
[Judd] Here's something I do
when it comes to food.
I always find a rationalization
why it's okay.
Really? You're the one that does that?
[both laughing]
Do you find there's anything with money
that makes you happy
more than simple things?
-Oh, yeah.
-[both laughing]
I never have anything I want to buy.
I have no item that I like
that costs anything.
-You have no taste.
-[laughing]
Both my kids are really funny,
and my daughter, who's 13,
the other night, she says,
"I don't want you and Mom to have sex."
And I go, "What are you talking about?"
And she goes, "Six months ago,
I walked up to the door
and I heard you have sex,
and it really freaked me out."
Maybe you were just trying
to get a plug in an outlet.
[laughing]
I think we were watching, like, Narcos.
-I think she heard Escobar have sex.
-[laughs] Yeah, right.
Actually, an interesting marker is,
at what age kids are allowed
to have tattoos without permission.
Never. I just don't like the idea of it.
Draw on a piece of paper
if you want to draw.
I could not make that any better.
I feel like I don't want
to know where this place is,
because I might just go back all the time.
It's like when I was a very young man,
I did mushrooms,
and I went to see Frank Sinatra
and Don Rickles on mushrooms.
And, my friend, on mushrooms,
was brought on stage by Rickles,
and we had the best night of our lives.
We talked about it for years.
We'd call each other and go,
"Best night of our lives, right?"
[Jerry laughing]
Afterwards, I said to my friend,
"Can I get more mushrooms?"
And he said,
"Oh, I lost the contact of the guy."
Because he could see in my eyes
I was about to do mushrooms
every day for the rest of my life.
-So, you relate that to this burger?
-Exactly.
Don't tell me where this diner is.
What is it when someone's funny?
Why do we love them so much?
When I was a kid, I loved that people
were saying "all of this makes no sense."
The whole setup of this life is crazy,
and who's rich and who's poor,
and who has power,
and the emotional life of people,
the spirituality,
and I love that comedians decoded it all.
I love that comedians do that.
I don't think I could survive without it.
[upbeat music playing]
[inaudible]
[Judd] When I was a kid,
my parents got divorced,
and my mother got a job seating people
at the East End Comedy Club...
-What?
-...in Southampton.
I could not have loved it more.
I watched every single show
for an entire summer.
I always thought
my mom couldn't have gotten paid
any money to seat people at a comedy club.
No.
What do you pay a woman
to seat people, 50 bucks?
And how embarrassing is it
as an upper middle class woman...
-Right.
-...who has a horrible divorce.
And she knew I loved comedy
And I think she must have, on some level,
thought, "Judd would love this."
That's sweet.
And I remember Lenny Schultz came in.
-And Lenny Schultz had that crazy act.
-Mmm-hmm.
And how it ended was
they put plastic down on the stage,
he would put on this Italian opera music,
he'd have a big thing of spaghetti,
and he would lip-sync
and throw the spaghetti in his face.
It ended, like, pouring milk over his head
and cracking eggs on his head.
-Yeah.
-And then he would come in the kitchen,
and jump in the giant sink,
and I would have to pour
buckets of water over his head
to get all the spaghetti and eggs
off of him.
And I could not have been happier.
I think we got that done.
-Fantastic.
-I think there's 17 minutes in there.
[Jerry] No question.
[both laughing]
Well, I don't necessarily believe in God.
Like, the only way I could process
being a human being
is to examine it, and learn,
and also to mock everything
and to see the ridiculousness of it,
because there's no order in my mind.
I don't even know
what you're talking about.
[Judd laughing]